Register of the Milan Gavrilović Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Milan Gavrilović papers
1938-1979
76072
Hoover Institution Archives
(9.9 linear feet) 66 microfilm reels, digital files
Correspondence, diaries, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, notes, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Yugoslav politics and government, relations between Yugoslavia and the Soviet Union, Yugoslavia during World War II, the Yugoslav government-in-exile, Draza Mihailovic and the Cetnik resistance movement in occupied Yugoslavia, and the activities of Serbian émigré groups following World War II. Also available on microfilm (66 reels).
Gavrilović, Milan, 1882-1976
Access
Reels 3-6 closed.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1882 December 6 Born, Belgrade, Serbia Receives elementary and secondary education in Eastern Serbia
1901 Enters Law School, University of Belgrade. Founds and edits the student paper Oslobodjenje. Works as a reporter for Dnevni List, a Belgrade daily
1902 Suspended for a year from the University for refusing to attend classes as a political protest
1905 During Easter vacation joins the chetniks to fight for the liberation of southern parts of Serbia. Wounded in the Battle of Čelopek
1906 Graduates from Law School, University of Belgrade
1907 Enters Law School, University of Paris
1911 Receives Doctorate of Law degree (Doctorat d'Etat), University of Paris. His dissertation ("L'état et le droit") was awarded French state prize. Joins Political Section, Serbian Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1912 Takes unofficial leave from the Ministry to fight in the Balkan War as a chetnik
1913-1916 Secretary to the Prime Minister and Minister of Foreign Affairs, Nikola Pašić
1914 Married Jelena Cincar-Janković
1916-1923 Serves in London (1916), Athens (1918), Berlin (1922), and Rome (1923), resigning from the service with the rank of Counselor
1920 Joins the newly founded Agrarian Party and is elected member of its Executive Committee
1921-38 Vice President, Serbian Agrarian Party
1923 Publishes a monograph, A Political and Economic Democracy, which is adopted as the platform of the Serbian Agrarian Party
1923-1930 Editor-in-Chief, Politika (Belgrade)
1930 Because of pressures on Politika exerted by the personal regime of King Aleksandar, is forced to leave the paper
1936-1937 Plays major part in negotiating an agreement between Croat leader Dr. Maček and Serbian opposition parties
1938-1976 President, Serbian Agrarian Party
1940-1941 Royal Envoy of Yugoslavia to the Soviet Union
1941 Minister (without portfolio) in the General Simović Government
1942-1943 Minister of Justice in the Yugoslav Government in Exile, London
1950 Settles in the United States President of the Serbian National Federation and the Serbian National Defense. Executive member of the International Peasant Union. Publishes many articles on Communism in English and Serbian, two of which are entered into the Congressional Record ("What Now?" House, 1956, pp. A1741-2; "Street Mobs and Soviet Foreign Policy," Senate, 1960, pp. 15421-2). Resigns from all official positions after his eightieth birthday in 1962, but remains active until shortly before his death, writing monographs and articles and maintaining a voluminous correspondence
1976 January 1 Dies, Bethesda, Maryland, and is buried in the Serbian Orthodox Monastery of Saint Sava in Libertyville near Chicago, Illinois
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, diaries, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, notes, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Yugoslav politics and government, relations between Yugoslavia and the Soviet Union, Yugoslavia during World War II, the Yugoslav government-in-exile, Draza Mihailovic and the Cetnik resistance movement in occupied Yugoslavia, and the activities of Serbian émigré groups following World War II. Also available on microfilm (66 reels).
Mihailović, Draža, 1893-1946.; Diplomats--Yugoslavia.; Russia (Federation); Serbs in foreign countries.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--Yugoslavia.; Soviet Union.; Statesmen--Yugoslavia.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Underground movements.; World War, 1939-1945--Yugoslavia.; World War, 1939-1945.; Yugoslavia--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; Yugoslavia--History--Axis occupation, 1941-1945.; Yugoslavia--Politics and government.; Yugoslavia.
- Biographical File, 1940-1976 (Reel 1, Box 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, certificates, membership cards, reports, passports and clippings relating to the career and life of Milan Gavrilović. Arranged alphabetically by form or subject
  - General (Reel 1, Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Biographical notes (Reel 1, Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Clippings (Reel 1, Box-folder 1: 3-4)
  - Identity papers (marriage certificate, membership cards, passports) (Box-folder 1: 5, Reel 1)
  - Subject file
    - Free Europe Committee, Milan Gavrilović's affiliation with, 1964 (Reel 1, Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Immigration status and permanent residency in the United States, 1951-1957 (Reel 2, Box-folder 1: 7-8)
    - Travel between the United Kingdom and United States, 1951-1958 (Reel 2, Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Writings by various authors relating to Milan Gavrilović's diplomatic career (Box-folder 2: 2, Reel 2)
- Diaries, 1940-1959 (Box 2, Reel 2-2A)
  Handwritten and typewritten diaries arranged chronologically
  - 1940-1943 (Box-folder 2: 3, Reel 2)
  - 1942-1945 (Box-folder 2: 4-5, Reel 3)
  - 1944-1949 (Box-folder 2: 6, Reel 3)
  - 1950-1959 (Box-folder 2: 7, Reel 3)
- Correspondence, 1941-1975 (Box 3-19, Reel 3-22)
  Correspondence including attachments. Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - General
    Access
    Reels 3-6 (Boxes 3-5) Closed.
    - General
      - Undated (Box-folder 3: 1, Reel 3)
      - 1941-1949 (Reel 3, Box-folder 3: 2)
      - 1950-1959 (Reel 3, Box-folder 3: 3)
      - 1960-1969 (Reel 3, Box-folder 3: 4)
      - 1970-1975 (Reel 3, Box-folder 3: 5)
    - Gavrilović family correspondence
      - Undated (Reel 3-4, Box-folder 3: 6-7)
      - Undated (Reel 4-5, Box-folder 4: 1-6)
      - 1940-1949 (Reel 5, Box-folder 4: 7)
      - 1950-1952 (Reel 5, Box-folder 5: 1)
      - 1953-1956 (Box-folder 5: 2, Reel 5)
      - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 5: 3, Reel 6)
      - 1959-1976 (Box-folder 5: 4, Reel 6)
  - Unidentified (Box-folder 5: 5, Reel 6)
  - Aćin, Miloš Kosta, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 6: 1, Reel 7)
  - Aleksić, Bogosav
    - 1948-1963 (Box-folder 6: 2, Reel 7)
    - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 6: 3, Reel 7)
    - 1966-1969 (Box-folder 6: 4, Reel 7)
    - 1970-1972 (Box-folder 6: 5, Reel 7)
  - Aleksić, Jovan, 1963 (Reel 7, Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Aleksić, Milinko D., 1960-1970 (Box-folder 6: 7, Reel 7)
  - Aleksić, Panta, 1969 (Reel 8, Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Allied Circle, 1944 (Box-folder 6: 9, Reel 8)
  - Altmayer, Jakob, 1944-1961 (Box-folder 6: 10, Reel 8)
  - American Association of Former Yugoslav Military Prisoners of War, n.d. (Box-folder 6: 11, Reel 8)
  - American Institute for Balkan Affairs, 1956 (Box-folder 6: 12, Reel 8)
  - American-Serbian Democratic Anticommunist Committee, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 6: 13, Reel 8)
  - Amery, Julian, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 6: 14, Reel 8)
  - Andrews, Henry M., 1942-1948 (Reel 8, Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Andrić, Živorad, 1948 (Reel 8, Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Annunzio, Frank, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 7: 1, Reel 8)
  - Antić, Bora (Serbian People's University), 1958 (Box-folder 7: 2, Reel 8)
  - Arsenijević, Čedomir (Savez Zemljoradnika) and Anica, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 7: 3, Reel 8)
  - Atanatskovitch (Atanacković), Milena, 1956 (Box-folder 7: 4, Reel 8)
  - Atholl, Katharine Marjory, Duchess of, 1944-1948 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Aucouturier, Gustave, 1958-1961 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Avakumović, A. G., 1946-1960 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Avakumović, Ivan, 1971-1972 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Avramović, Lazar, 1962-1975 (Box-folder 7: 9, Reel 8)
  - Bajčetić, Milutin, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 7: 10, Reel 8)
  - Balentine, Ms., 1956 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Bancroft, R. F. L. (British Museum, Reading Room), 1964 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Bandović, Milan, 1948-1970 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Beddington-Behrens, E., 1949-1950 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Begović, Božidar, 1948-1970 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Blau, Alphonse A., 1961 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Blazas, Henrikas, 1958-1965 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Bodi, Milan, 1945 (Box-folder 7: 18, Reel 8)
  - Bogdanov, Stojan, 1960 (Box-folder 7: 19, Reel 8)
  - Bögholm, K., 1946 (Box-folder 7: 20, Reel 8)
  - Bogić, 1942 (Box-folder 7: 21, Reel 8)
  - Bojović, Nikola, 1950-1975 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Bokor, Bela, 1956-1960 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Bolton, J. R. Glorney, 1948 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Bonnet, Henri, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 25, Reel 8)
  - Borjanović, Bogdan, 1948 (Reel 8, Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Božić, Ljubiša, 1946 (Reel 9, Box-folder 7: 27)
  - Brašić, Ranko M. and Mrs., 1950-1973 (Reel 9, Box-folder 7: 28)
  - Braunović, Draško, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 7: 29, Reel 9)
  - Brekić, Stojan D., 1972 (Reel 9, Box-folder 7: 30)
  - British and Foreign Bible Society, 1944 (Box-folder 7: 31, Reel 9)
  - Brkić, Jovan, 1961-1974 (Reel 9, Box-folder 7: 32)
  - Brown, Spencer Curtis, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 7: 33, Reel 9)
  - Bukara, Milutin, 1960-1962 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Bulajić, Božo, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 8: 2, Reel 9)
  - Bulat, Pero (Serbian National Shield Society of Canada), 1954-1969 (Box-folder 8: 3, Reel 9)
  - Bulatović, M. L., 1971 (Box-folder 8: 4, Reel 9)
  - Bunjević, Dušan, 1958 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Burojević, Dragiša, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 8: 6, Reel 9)
  - Buzolić, Mihovil, 1956-1959 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Byrd, Robert C., 1956 (Box-folder 8: 8, Reel 9)
  - Canberra Times, 1970 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Cankov, Aleksandar C., 1946 (Box-folder 8: 10, Reel 9)
  - Catholic University of America, 1971 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Čemović, Filip, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 8: 12, Reel 9)
  - Černy, Frantiŝek, 1960 (Box-folder 8: 13, Reel 9)
  - Cerović, Milutin G. (Njegos), 1973 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Chuk, Peter, 1961 (Box-folder 8: 15, Reel 9)
  - Ćićarić, Miroslav, 1971 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Ciliga, Ante, 1947 (Box-folder 8: 17, Reel 9)
  - Ciolkosz, Adam, 1958 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 18)
  - Ćirić, Ljuba, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 19, Reel 9)
  - Club Culturel National Serbe en Suisse, 1962 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Club Fédéral de l'Europe Centrale, 1948 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Club Karadjordje, 1965-1968 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Clube Serbo Brasileiro em Sao Paulo, 1969 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Čok, Jan M., 1942 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Colgan, Mary (Woman's Club of Middlesborough), 1951-1952 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Committee for a Free Asia (Geen, George H., Jr.), 1951 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 26)
  - Cook, Thomas, Sir, 1944 (Reel 9, Box-folder 8: 27)
  - Čopić, Milorad, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 8: 28, Reel 9)
  - Cordier, Louis, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 8: 29, Reel 9)
  - Coren, Alexander, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 30, Reel 9)
  - Ćorković, Nenad, 1946 (Box-folder 8: 31, Reel 9)
  - Cripps, Stafford, Sir, 1943 (Box-folder 8: 32, Reel 9)
  - Crnogorac, Milorad, 1948-1968 (Box-folder 8: 33, Reel 9)
  - Čubrilović, Branko, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 8: 34, Reel 9)
  - Ćuk, Walter M., 1942 (Box-folder 8: 35, Reel 10)
  - Cvejić, Milorad, 1971-1973 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 36)
  - Cvetković, Dragiša, 1946-1947 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 37)
  - Cvijanović, Djordje B., 1947-1948 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 38)
  - Cvorovic, Rad, 1957-1966 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 39)
  - Czechoslovak Agrarian Information Bureau, London, 1948 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 40)
  - Damjanović, Miodrag, 1948 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 41)
  - Detar, Maria-N., 1963 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 42)
  - Dilley, Francis and Margo, 1965 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 43)
  - Dimitrijević, Aleksandar, 1945 (Box-folder 8: 44, Reel 10)
  - Dimitrijević, B., 1963 (Box-folder 8: 45, Reel 10)
  - Dimitrijević, Mladen, 1967 (Boxes 8: 46, Reel 10)
  - Dimitrijević, Sotir, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 47, Reel 10)
  - Dimitrov, Georgi (George) M. (President of the Bulgarian Agrarian Party), 1948-1967 (Box-folder 8: 48, Reel 10)
  - Divjak, Milorad, 1944-1948 (Box-folder 8: 49, Reel 10)
  - Djelevich, Jakša V., n.d. (Box-folder 8: 50, Reel 10)
  - Djokić, Aleksandar, 1956 (Box-folder 8: 51, Reel 10)
  - Djoković, Trivun, 1948 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 52)
  - Djonović, Jovan (Delegate, Royal Yugoslav Government, Middle East), 1944-1953 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 53)
  - Djordjević, Milutin A., 1943 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 54)
  - Djordjević, V., 1963 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 55)
  - Djorić, Jovanka, 1956 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 56)
  - Djujić, Momćilo Vojvoda (Pokret Srpskih Četnika Ravne Gore), 1958-1963 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 57)
  - Djurić, Milivoje, 1947 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 58)
  - Djurišić, Vidak J., 1962 (Reel 10, Box-folder 8: 59)
  - Dobrivojević, R. D., 1961-68 (Box-folder 8: 60, Reel 10)
  - Dodd, Thomas J. (U.S. Senator for Connecticut), 1960-1962 (Box-folder 8: 61, Reel 10)
  - Dorsey, Benjamin H., 1954-1955 (Box-folder 8: 62, Reel 10)
  - Dragnich, Alex N., 1972 (Box-folder 8: 63, Reel 10)
  - Dragosavljević, Stanko (Serbian National Defense Council of America), 1959-1963 (Box-folder 8: 64, Reel 10)
  - Drašković, Slobodan M. (Serbian Cultural Club "Sveti Sava"), 1969 (Box-folder 8: 65, Reel 10)
  - Drummond, Roscoe, 1973 (Box-folder 8: 66, Reel 10)
  - Dučić, Mihailo and Leposava (Serbian National Defense Council of America), 1948 (Box-folder 9: 1, Microfilm 10)
  - Dukić, Dušan, 1948 (Box-folder 9: 2, Reel 10)
  - Dunjić, Djordje (Communauté Serbe en Belgique), 1960-1970 (Box-folder 9: 3, Reel 10)
  - Džambazović, Radivoje G., 1954 (Box-folder 9: 4, Reel 10)
  - Easterman, A. L. (World Jewish Congress), 1943 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Emmet, Christopher, 1955 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Erith, Charles H., 1949 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Fabian International Bureau, 1942 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Farcasanu, Mihai M., 1956 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Farkaš, Vekoslav, 1944-1948 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Feierabend, L. K., 1943-1957 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Filipović, Lazar, 1942 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Firmilijan, Bishop (Serbian Orthodox Midwest Diocese), 1963 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Fond Nacionalne Borbe (Serbian National Fund), 1969-1971 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Ford, Kirk, Jr., 1973 (Box-folder 9: 15, Reel 10)
  - Fotić, Konstantin, 1945-1947 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 16)
  - France. Mission Auprès du Gouvernement Royal de Yugoslavie, 1944 (Box-folder 9: 17, Reel 10)
  - Free Citizens of Yugoslavia, 1950-1955 (Box-folder 9: 18, Reel 10)
  - Fund Chetniks Invalids, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 19, Reel 10)
  - Furniss, Spencer L., 1942 (Box-folder 9: 20, Reel 10)
  - Gachovich, Nasif N., 1947-1969 (Reel 10, Box-folder 9: 21)
  - Gajić, Božidar, 1970 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 22)
  - Galmard, L., 1965 (Box-folder 9: 23, Reel 11)
  - Garčev, Triva and Mrs., 1969-1972 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 24)
  - Gifford, Charles, 1941 (Box-folder 9: 25, Reel 11)
  - Gjurkovečki, Mirko, 1956 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 26)
  - Glennon, Mr., n.d. (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 27)
  - Gligorievich, M., n.d. (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 28)
  - Gniezović, Branko and Ruža (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 29)
  - Godfrey, W., 1944 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 30)
  - Godjevatz, Velizar, 1973 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 31)
  - Golubović, Zagorka, 1961-1962 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 32)
  - Gowen, Mr., 1952 (Box-folder 9: 33, Reel 11)
  - Grdjić, Radmilo, 1956 (Box-folder 9: 34, Reel 11)
  - Great Britain. Ministry of Home Security, 1945 (Box-folder 9: 35, Reel 11)
  - Greenlees, K., 1946 (Box-folder 9: 35, Reel 11)
  - Grenfell, A. M., 1949 (Box-folder 9: 37, Reel 11)
  - Grković, Aleksa, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 9: 38, Reel 11)
  - Gross, Feliks (New York University), 1952 (Box-folder 9: 39, Reel 11)
  - Hadija, Kosta Dj., 1950 (Box-folder 9: 40, Reel 11)
  - Hall, Mollie, 1955 (Box-folder 9: 41, Reel 11)
  - Heathcote-Smith, Clifford E., Sir (Refugees Defense Committee), 1946-1951 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 42)
  - Heymann, Egon, 1947 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 43)
  - Hooten, Rex, Mrs., 1963 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 44)
  - Hoptner, J. B., 1952-1953 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 45)
  - Hristić, Bosa, 1942 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 46)
  - Hudak, Albert, 1950 (Box-folder 9: 47, Reel 11)
  - Huysmans, Camille, 1943 (Box-folder 9: 48, Reel 11)
  - Ignjatovich, Ranko S., n.d. (Box-folder 9: 49, Reel 11)
  - Ilić, Vojislav, 1946 (Box-folder 9: 50, Reel 11)
  - International Co-Operative Alliance, 1942-1943 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 51)
  - Ioann, Archbishop (San Francisco and the Western United States), 1963 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 52)
  - Irinej (Bishop of Dalmatia), 1945-1947 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 53)
  - Ivanković, Petar, 1942 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 54)
  - Ivanović, Vane (Free Citizens of Yugoslavia), 1949-1963 (Box-folder 9: 55, Reel 11)
  - Janketić, Miro, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 56, Reel 11)
  - Janković, Janko, 1945-1970 (Box-folder 9: 57, Reel 11)
  - Jefremović, Draga, 1946-1963 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 58)
  - Jelesijević, Lazar, 1968 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 59)
  - Jelisavcić, Mihailo, 1942-1975 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 60)
  - Jerić, A. R. K., 1955-1971 (Box-folder 9: 61, Reel 11)
  - Jevrić, 1966 (Box-folder 9: 62, Reel 11)
  - Jevtić, Milorad, 1951-1967 (Box-folder 9: 63, Reel 11)
  - Jevtić-Fortner, Ikonija, 1967 (Box-folder 9: 64, Reel 11)
  - Jlitsch, Lubinko, n.d. (Box-folder 9: 65, Reel 11)
  - Joint International Committee of Movements for European Unity, 1948 (Box-folder 9: 66, Reel 11)
  - Jovanović, Jovan, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 9: 67, Reel 11)
  - Jovanović, Milan, n.d. (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 68)
  - Jovanović, Milorad V., 1953-1954 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 69)
  - Jovanović, Radm., 1963-1968 (Reel 11, Box-folder 9: 70)
  - Jovanović, Slobodan (Prime Minister, Royal Yugoslav Government) (Box 10)
    - Undated (Reel 11, Box-folder 10: 1)
    - 1942-1953 (Box-folder 10: 2, Reel 11)
    - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 10: 3, Reel 11)
    - 1956-1958 (Reel 12, Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Jovanović, Vlasta K., 1963-1966 (Reel 12, Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Jovetić, Jovan, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 10: 6, Reel 12)
  - Jovović, Jakov, 1950-1957 (Reel 12, Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Jovović, Milosav, 1947-1960 (Box-folder 10: 8, Reel 12)
  - Kajmaković, Omer, 1947-1962 (Box-folder 10: 9, Reel 12)
  - Kandić, Jagoš, 1964 (Box-folder 10: 10, Reel 12)
  - Karadjordjević, Alexander, Prince (Box-folder 10: 11, Reel 12)
  - Karadjordjević, Pavle, Prince, 1970 (Box-folder 10: 12, Reel 12)
  - Karadjordjević, Tomislav, Prince, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 10: 13, Reel 12)
  - Kasiković, Dragiša, 1962 (Box-folder 10: 14, Reel 12)
  - Kearns, Carroll D., 1961 (Box-folder 10: 15, Reel 12)
  - Keating, Kenneth B., 1962 (Box-folder 10: 16, Reel 12)
  - Kerekes, Tibor (Institute of Ethnic Studies, Georgetown University), 1960-1961 (Box-folder 10: 17, Reel 12)
  - Kincaid, Robert L. (Lincoln Memorial University), 1953-1954 (Reel 12, Box-folder 10: 18)
  - King Peter II Foundation, 1973 (Reel 12, Box-folder 10: 19)
  - Klajević, Krsto, 1967-1969 (Reel 12, Box-folder 10: 20)
  - Knežević, Živan and Mrs., 1953-1960 (Reel 12, Box-folder 10: 21)
  - Knežević, Radoje L., 1951-1974 (Box-folder 10: 22, Reel 12)
  - Koce, Jure, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 10: 23, Reel 12)
  - Kojić, Veljko M., 1948 (Box-folder 10: 24, Reel 12)
  - Kolarović, Svetislav, 1968 (Box-folder 10: 25, Reel 12)
  - Konjhodzich, Alija S., 1957-1970 (Reel 12, Box-folder 10: 26)
  - Kontić, Jovan M., 1958-1967 (Box-folder 10: 27, Reel 12)
  - Korac, Rade, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 10: 28, Reel 12)
  - Korbel, Josef, 1951 (Box-folder 10: 29, Reel 12)
  - Kosić, Nikola, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 10: 30, Reel 12)
  - Kostić, Boško N., 1947 (Box-folder 10: 31, Reel 12)
  - Kovacic, Milan, 1952 (Box-folder 11: 1, Reel 12)
  - Kovatchevitch, Mihailo N., 1948-1965 (Box-folder 11: 2, Reel 12)
  - Krajšumović, Kosta, 1942-1948 (Box-folder 11: 3, Reel 12)
  - Krek, Miha, 1942-1969 (Reel 12, Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Krnjević, Juraj, 1944-1950 (Reel 12, Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Krstic, Dobroslav S., 1968-1975 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Kuhar, Aloiz, 1942-1956 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Kumdžijaš, Milan, 1952 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Kuncewicz, I., 1945 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Kusonjich, Branko, 1961 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Kuveljich, Vukich S., 1954 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 11)
  - Lane, Arthur Bliss, 1955 (Box-folder 11: 12, Reel 13)
  - Langer, William, 1955 (Box-folder 11: 13, Reel 13)
  - Latvia. Minister to Great Britain (Charles Zarins), 1947 (Box-folder 11: 14, Reel 13)
  - Lazarević, Dimitrije, 1948-1960 (Box-folder 11: 15, Reel 13)
  - Lazarević, Dušan, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 11: 16, Reel 13)
  - Lazarević, Jaroslav, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 17, Reel 13)
  - Lazarević, Radovan, 1961 (Box-folder 11: 18, Reel 13)
  - Lazić, Miloš M., 1945 (Box-folder 11: 19, Reel 13)
  - Lazić, Vukašin Pop, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 20, Reel 13)
  - Lazović, Dragutin, 1955-1962 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 21)
  - Lebedeff, Vl., 1943 (Box-folder 11: 22, Reel 13)
  - Lettrich, Jozef, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 23, Reel 13)
  - Liberal International, 1948 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 24)
  - Lilich, Milutin P., 1960 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 25)
  - Lipovac, Špiro and Tanja, 1974 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 26)
  - Lipovatz, V. de, 1969 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 27)
  - Loeb, Walter, 1944 (Box-folder 11: 28, Reel 13)
  - Logan, Kenneth C., 1948 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 29)
  - Lončarić, Andra, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 11: 30, Reel 13)
  - Lucas, M. B., n.d. (Box-folder 11: 31, Reel 13)
  - Lukić, Milorad, 1950 (Box-folder 11: 32, Reel 13)
  - Lukić, Uroš, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 33, Reel 13)
  - Lunde, Ivar and Marie, 1959 (Box-folder 11: 34, Reel 13)
  - Maček, Vladko, 1946-1964 (Box-folder 11: 35, Reel 13)
  - Mačogi, Milinko, 1962 (Box-folder 11: 36, Reel 13)
  - MacPhail, K.S., 1942 (Box-folder 11: 37, Reel 13)
  - Maksimovic, Nick, 1975 (Box-folder 11: 38, Reel 13)
  - Mandel, Benjamin (Senate Internal Security Subcommittee), 1962 (Box-folder 11: 39, Reel 13)
  - Mandouchitch, Janko, 1946 (Box-folder 11: 40, Reel 13)
  - Manojlović, Draginja, 1970 (Box-folder 11: 41, Reel 13)
  - Marjanović, Dobrivoje, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 11: 42, Reel 13)
  - Marković, Ivan, 1946 (Box-folder 11: 43, Reel 13)
  - Marković, Lazar Z., 1943-1965 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 44)
  - Marković, Milorad, 1954-1960 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 45)
  - Marković-Grljanac, Lj., 1952-1954 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 46)
  - Martin, David, 1946-1969 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 47)
  - Mašić, Mr., 1960 (Reel 13, Box-folder 11: 48)
  - Matić, Momčilo, 1960 (Box-folder 11: 49, Reel 13)
  - McHale, Edward J., 1953-1957 (Box-folder 12: 1, Reel 14)
  - Medenica, Ranko, 1965 (Box-folder 12: 2, Reel 14)
  - Meinl, J. H., 1944 (Box-folder 12: 3, Reel 14)
  - Melville, C. F., 1943 (Box-folder 12: 4, Reel 14)
  - Middlesborough Chamber of Commerce, Kentucky (Reams, Hobart W.), 1954 (Box-folder 12: 5, Reel 14)
  - Mid-European Studies Center, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 12: 6, Reel 14)
  - Mihailović, Aleksander, 1947 (Box-folder 12: 7, Reel 14)
  - Mihajlović, Dušan, 1947 (Box-folder 12: 8, Reel 14)
  - Mihajlović, Marko (Box-folder 12: 9, Reel 14)
  - Mihailović, P., 1943 (Box-folder 12: 10, Reel 14)